(iii)



Constantly fueled with curiosity and boundless enthusiasm, I am a multidisciplinary product designer who enjoys crafting delightful, useful and equally meaningful product experiences. In a parallel universe, I am busy doodling the world around me or documenting my daily life through dataviz or exploring music.

EDUCATION

June 2012 - Jan 2015 M.Des, Industrial Design

National Institute of Design

Ahmedabad, India

Final Year Project:

Connected Homes- Smart Hub an Ecosystem for Residential Fire Sal Sponsor - Honeywell, India

Sept 2013- Mar 2014 Student Exchange Program - DAAD Fellowship

Hochschule Fur Technik und Wirtschaft

Berlin, Germany

Main Projects:

Smart PPE, Safety Headphones for an Industrial Worker Sponsor- UVEX GmbH

2. Technical Construction Toy for Kids Sponsor – Eitech GmbH

July 2007- April 2012 B.Arch, Bachelors in Architecture

Visvesvaraya National Institute of Technology

Nagpur, India

Design Thesis: Future Libraries, The Theatre of Knowledge Dissertation: Emergence Architecture and Technologies,

in Architecture

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2015 - Present Senior Designer

Honeywell Technology Solutions Lab. Bangalore, India

Performance Materials & Technologies

Worked on various types of projects at different levels of the product cycle, from concept phase till release. As a hybrid designer, I have been involved in UI, UX and industrial design projects, most of which have been successfully launched and released in market. I was also a part of the cross-business innovation team, where I contributed for blue sky ideas and developed quick proof of concepts. I have worked closely with developers, engineers, marketing and product managers for every project. Developed apps spanning across multiple platforms including ios, android, windows (enterprise applications).

Certification - Honeywell Six Sigma Green Belt Beginner Training - Designing for Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality

May 2014 - Dec 2014

Honeywell Technology Solutions Lab. Bangalore, India

Worked with Honeywell automation and control systems team for final year design project on the topic of connected homes for Indian context. With the focus on residential fire safety systems, I designed a product and an app system for early detection of fire hazards. In parallel to this, I helped Honeywell aerospace team to design

aircraft cargo lighting.

July 2011- Dec 2011 Architecture Intern

VDGA Architects. Pune. India

Primarily worked on space design of boutique projects in residential and hospitality sector. Also, acquired hands on experience working with artisans, carpenters, consultants on site.

AWARDS

Aug 2017	Honeywell Bronze Act with Urgency Award
Feb 2017	HTS Annual User Experience Award
Dec 2016	Partner Award- Customer Sales Win
Nov 2016	HTS PMT - Velocity Product Developement Award
June 2016	Honeywell Silver - Technology and Innovation Award
Dec 2015	HTS Annual User Experience Award

Citation: Art of Relevance, Ar. Gautam Bhatia

Competition by IA&B Magazine.(2009)

Citation: Landscape Ideas trophy,

Annual SAARC NASA* Competition.(2010) *National Association of Students of Architectur

SKILLS

Design Thinking . User Experience . Information Design . Interaction Design . Industrial Design . User Research . Agile and Lean Processes . Dataviz . Storyboarding . 3D Modelling and Rendering . Journey Maps . Personas . 360 Degree Experience Mapping . Low-Fid Wireframing . High-Fid Visual Design . Quick Ideation . Mockups +RP . CMF Design . Paper + Digital Interactive Prototyping . Illustrations

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, Indesign, XD). Sketch . Rhinoceros 3D . Invision App . Framer . Proto.io . Marvel . Principal . KeyShot . AutoCAD 2D,3D . Sketchup . Autodesk Sketchbook Pro . Procreate . Unity 3D (Beginner)